<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article id="TEI"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"  xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation='http://www.docbook.org/xsd/4.4/docbook.xsd'>
<articleinfo>
        <author>
            <firstname>Conal</firstname>
            <surname>Tuohy</surname>
        </author>
        <copyright>
            <year>2019</year>
            <holder>Conal Tuohy</holder>
        </copyright>

        <legalnotice>
            <title>Legal Notice</title>

            <para>Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
            document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License,
            Version 1.1 or any later version published by the Free Software
            Foundation; with no <quote>Invariant Sections</quote>,
            <quote>Front-Cover Texts</quote> or <quote>Back-Cover Texts</quote>,
            each as defined in the license. A copy of the license is included in
            the file <filename>COPYING.DOC.txt</filename> included with the
            jEdit distribution.</para>
        </legalnotice>
        <title>jEdit TEI Plugin</title>
</articleinfo>
<section>
        <title>Introduction</title>

        <indexterm>
            <primary>TEI</primary>
        </indexterm>

        <para>This plugin provides tools for text encoding using an XML vocabulary called
        Text Encoding for Interchange (TEI).</para>

        <para>For more information about TEI, visit the <ulink url="https://tei-c.org/">website
        of the <orgname>Text Encoding Initiative Consortium</orgname></ulink>. </para>
</section>
<section>
        <title>Operation</title>

        <para><indexterm>
                <primary>TEI</primary>

                <secondary>shortcut keys</secondary>
            </indexterm>The TEI plugin provides the following keyboard shortcuts</para>
</section>
<section>
        <title>Toolbar buttons</title>

        <para>The TEI toolbar contains the following buttons:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The <guilabel>Update TEI Package</guilabel> button
                downloads a package of TEI-related files from the TEI 
                Consortium's website.
                To specify a different location to download the package from,
                use the <link
                linkend="options">options dialog</link>.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>The <guilabel>New TEI file from template</guilabel> button
                opens a hierarchical menu of TEI template files, provided by the TEI package. 
                Selecting one of the templates will create a new document based on the selected template.</para>
            </listitem>

        </itemizedlist>

        <para>These operations are also listed in the menu which appears for
        TEI under the <guimenu>Plugins</guimenu> heading. </para>

</section>
<section id="options">
        <title>Options</title>

        <indexterm>
            <primary>TEI</primary>

            <secondary>options</secondary>
        </indexterm>

        <para>There are two options which can be set using the pane for
        TEI in the <guilabel>Plugin Shortcuts</guilabel> section of the
        general options dialog:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The <guilabel>Auto-update TEI package</guilabel> checkbox causes the TEI Plugin
                to check for updates to the TEI package and download them automatically.</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
                <para>The <guilabel>TEI package update URL</guilabel> field specifies the location of a metadata
                resource which lists the avaiable versions of the TEI package. When the TEI Consortium updates
                the package metadata resource to point to a new package, the TEI Plugin will download and install the new package.</para>
            </listitem>

        </itemizedlist>
</section>
<section>
        <title>Legal notices</title>

        <para>The TEI plugin is released under the GNU General Public
        License (either version 2 or any later version, at the user's option). A
        copy of the GPL is available in the <filename>COPYING.txt</filename>
        file in the jEdit distribution.</para>

        <para>The TEI plugin comes with ABSOLUTELY NO WARRANTY OF ANY
        KIND; see section 11 and 12 of the GPL for details.</para>

        <para>Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
        document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version
        1.1 or any later version published by the Free Software Foundation; with
        no <quote>Invariant Sections</quote>, <quote>Front-Cover Texts</quote>
        or <quote>Back-Cover Texts</quote>, each as defined in the license. A
        copy of the license is included in the file
        <filename>COPYING.DOC.txt</filename> included with the jEdit
        distribution.</para>
</section>
<section>
        <title>Feedback</title>

        <para>Comments, bug reports and other feedback may be sent to the jEdit-users
        mailing list.</para>
</section>
</article>
